《哈利波特与死亡圣器（下）》
(多比长眠于此  一个自由的精灵)
It's beautiful here.
这儿真美
It was our aunt's. We used to come here as kids.
是姨妈的房子，小时候我们常来玩
The Order uses it now as a safe house.
现在是凤凰社的藏身地
What's left of us at least.
总算还有个住处
Muggles think these things keep evil away.
麻瓜认为风铃能辟邪
But they're wrong.
其实没用的
I need to talk to the Goblin.
我要跟妖精谈谈
How are you?
您怎么样了？
Alive.
还活着
You probably don't remember that you--
您可能已经不记得…
That I showed you to your vault, the first time you came to Gringotts.
记得你第一次来古灵阁时，就是我带你去的金库？
Even amongst Goblins, you are famous Harry Potter.
即使在妖精界你也相当有名，哈利·波特
- You buried the elf? - Yes.
- 你安葬了那只精灵？ - 是的
And brought me here.
还救我到这儿
You are...
你真是…
Pretty unusual, is it?
与众不同啊
How did you come by the sword?
你是怎么得到宝剑的？
It's complicated.
说来话长
Why did Bellatrix Lestrange think it should be in her vault at Gringotts?
贝拉特里克斯·莱斯特兰奇的金库里有什么？
It's complicated.
说来话长
The sword presented itself to us, in moment of need.
宝剑是自己出现的，在我们需要的时候
We didn't steal it.
我们没偷
There is a sword in Madam Lestrange's vault identical to this one.
莱斯特兰奇夫人的金库里有把一模一样的宝剑
But it is a fake.
但那把是假的
It was placed there this past summer.
夏天时被人调包了
And she never suspected it was a fake.
而她从没怀疑过那是假的？
The replica is very convincing.
因为它仿得十分逼真
Only a goblin would recognize that this is the true Sword of Gryffindor.
只有妖精才能看出来这把才是真的格兰芬多宝剑
Who is the acquaintance?
是谁调的包？
A Hogwarts Professor.
霍格沃茨的一位教授
As I understand that he's now Headmaster.
就我所知他现在是校长
Snape.
斯内普
He put a fake sword in Bellatrix's vault.
如果莱斯特兰奇金库里的是赝品…
Why?
怎么会？
There are more than a few curious things in the vaults at Gringotts.
古灵阁金库里的秘密可不止一两个
And in Madam Lestrange's vault as well?
莱斯特兰奇夫人的金库里也有秘密么？
Perhaps.
也许吧
I need to get into Gringotts. Into one of the vaults.
我要进入古灵阁，进一个金库
- It is impossible. - Alone, yes.
- 绝无可能 - 我自己确实不可能
But with you, no.
但是有你在，就可能
- Why should I help you? - I have gold.
- 我为什么要帮你？ - 我有金币
Lots of it.
很多很多金币
I've no interest in gold.
我对金币不感兴趣
Then what?
那你要什么？
That.
那个
That is my price.
那就是我的开价
Are you thinking there's a Horcrux in Bellatrix's vault?
你觉得贝拉特里克斯的金库里有魂器？
Well, she was terrified when she thought we had been in there.
她以为我们去过金库，都吓疯了
She kept asking you, what else was taken?
不停问我，还拿了什么东西
I bet you anything, there's Horcrux in there. Another piece of his soul.
我敢肯定那里有魂器，有他灵魂的一部分
Let's find it, kill it, and we are one step closer to killing him.
我们去找，销毁魂器，就离杀死他更近了一步
And what happens when we find it,
可是如果你把宝剑给了拉环
How're we supposed to destroy it, now you're giving the sword to Griphook?
我们找到魂器后要怎么销毁啊？
I'm still working on that part.
这我还没想好
He's weak.
他很虚弱
Who?
哈利！
Mr. Ollivander
奥利凡德先生…
I need to ask you a few questions.
我有些问题需要问你
Anything, m'boy. Anything!
可以，孩子，在所不辞
Would you mind identifying this wand? We need to know if it's safe to use.
能帮我鉴定下这根魔杖吗？ 我想知道用它安不安全
Uhh... Walnut
嗯…胡桃木
Dragon Heartstring
龙心弦
12 and three quarter inches.
12.75英寸
Unyie...
不易…
Unyielding.
不易弯曲
This belonged to Bellatrix Lestrange.
这根魔杖属于贝拉特里克斯·莱斯特兰奇
Try this carefully.
小心使用
And this?
这根呢？
Hawthorn.
山楂木
An unicorn hair.
独角兽毛
10 inches.
10英寸
Reasonably pliant.
弹性适中
This was the wand of Draco Malfoy.
这曾是德拉科·马尔福的
Was?
曾是？
Is it not still?
难道现在不是了？
Well, perhaps not. If you won it from him.
可能不是了，如果被你夺到的话
I sense its allegiance has changed.
我能感到它已改变了效忠对象
You talk about wands, as if they have feelings...
您把魔杖说得好像有感情一样…
.......can think!
还能思考
The wand chooses the wizard, Mr. Potter.
魔杖选择巫师，波特先生
That much has always been clear to those of us who've studied wandlore.
这对我们研究魔杖学问的人来说，一直很明确
And, what do you know about the Deathly Hallows?
那您知道死亡圣器么？
It is rumored there are three.
传说有三件圣器
The Elder Wand, the Cloak of Invisibility, to hide you from your enemies...
老魔杖、能让你躲避敌人的隐形衣
and the Resurrection Stone, to bring back loved ones from the dead.
还有复活石，能让你爱的人起死回生
Together, they make one the Master of Death.
同时拥有三件圣器，你就是死亡的主人
But few, truly believe that such objects exist.
但是，没几个人相信这种东西真的存在
Do you?
您呢？
Do you believe they exist, sir?
您相信它们存在吗，先生？
Well...
呃…
I see no reason to put stock into an old wives' tale.
我觉得没必要相信这老掉牙的传说吧
You're lying!
你在撒谎
You know one exists.
你知道有一件存在
You told him about it. You told him about the Elder Wand...
你告诉了他，你告诉了他老魔杖的事…
and where he could go looking for it.
还有去哪儿能找到它
He tortured me.
他拷问我
Besides...
但是…
....I only conveyed rumors.
我只是告诉了他传说
There's...
传说…
There's no telling whether he will find it.
传说并没有讲怎样能找到老魔杖
He has found it, sir.
他已经找到了，先生
We'll let you rest.
您好好休息吧
He's after you, Mr. Potter.
他在找你，波特先生
If it's true what you say,
如果你说的是真的
that he has the Elder Wand,
他找到了老魔杖
I'm afraid,
恐怕
...you really don't stand a chance.
你就真的没希望赢了
Well, I suppose I'll have to kill him, before he finds me, then.
那我就在他找到我之前杀了他
You're sure that's hers?
你肯定这是她的？
Positive.
肯定
Well?
怎样？
How do I look?
看起来如何？
Hideous.
好吓人
You can give that to Hermione to hold. Alright, Griphook?
可以让赫敏拿着剑吗，拉环？
We're relying on you, Griphook.
我们就靠你了，拉环
If you get us past the guards into the vault...
如果你能带我们穿过金库的守卫…
The sword's yours.
宝剑就归你
Madam Lestrange.
莱斯特兰奇夫人
Good morning.
早上好
Good morning? Good morning?
早上好？早上好？！
You're Bellatrix Lestrange, not some school girl!
你是贝拉特里克斯·莱斯特兰奇，不是小学生！
Hey! Easy!
嘿！冷静点！
If she gives us away, we must swear to use that sword to slit our own throats.
要是她漏了马脚，我们就只能用宝剑来自刎了
Understand?
明白吗？
No, he's right.
他说的对
I speak stupid.
我刚才傻死了
Okay. Let's do it.
好了，我们走
I wish to enter my vault.
我要去我的金库
Identification?
有身份证明么？
I hardly think that would be necessary.
我看没那个必要吧
Madam Lestrange.
莱斯特兰奇夫人
I don't like to be kept waiting.
我可不想等太久
I know...
他们知道了…
They know she's an impostor.
他们知道她是冒充的
They'd be warned.
他们一定得到了警告
Harry...
哈利…
What do we do, Harry?
怎么办啊，哈利？
Madam Lestrange, would you mind presenting your wand?
莱斯特兰奇夫人，可否请您出示下您的魔杖？
And why should I do that?
干嘛啊？
It's the bank's policy! I'm sure you understand, given current climate.
这是银行规定，请您务必谅解 现在形势特殊嘛
No! I most certainly do not understand!
不，我一点都不理解！
I'm afraid, I must insist.
抱歉，我必须要看
Imperio!
魂魄出窍！
Very well, Madam Lestrange.
好吧，莱斯特兰奇夫人
If you will follow me?
请跟我来
What is that, Griphook?
那是什么，拉环？
Griphook!
拉环？！
Aresto Momentum
减震咒！
Well done, Hermione.
干得好，赫敏
Oh no, you two're like you again.
遭了！你们俩又变回原样了
The Thief's Downfall, washes away all enchantments.
防贼瀑布会冲掉所有魔法
Can be deadly.
会很危险
You don't say.
我们出去吧
Just out of interest, is there any other way out of here?
顺便问下，这还有别的出路吗？
No.
没了
What the devil are all you doing down here?
你们有何企图，为什么来这？
Thieves!
小偷！
You gave up the.....
你不想再…
- Imperio - You!
- 魂魄出窍！- 你!
That doesn't sound good.
听上去不妙啊
Bloody hell!
天啊！
That's an Ukrainian Ironbelly.
这家伙怎么病怏怏的
Here.
拿着
It's been trained to expect pain when it hears the noise.
它受过训练，听到这个声音就会想到疼
That's barbaric!
真残忍！
Lumos
荧光闪烁
Blimey!
这么多
Accio Horcrux
魂器飞来！
You seem you're gonna try that one to get over here?
你想在这试飞来咒啊？
No kind of magic would work in here.
那种魔法在古灵阁里没用的
It's in here, Harry?
在这儿吗，哈利？
Can you feel anything?
你能感觉到吗？
That's it! Up there!
找到了！在那上边！
They have added the Gemino curse. Everything you touch will multiply.
他们在这施了复制咒，被碰到的东西都会自我复制
Give me the sword.
把剑给我
Stop moving!
别动了！
Do it!
抓住它！
- We had deal, Griphook! - The cup for the sword!
- 我们说好的，拉环！ - 拿剑来换金杯！
I said I'll get you in, I didn't say anything about getting you out.
我答应带你进来，可我没答应过带你出去
Griphook! Thieves! Griphook!
拉环！求你别走！拉环！
Hey, thieves!
嘿，怪兽！
Is that okay?
要是没有丁当片…
We've still got Bogrod.
那是鲍格罗德
That's unfortunate.
真是不幸
We can't just stand here, You got any idea?
我们不能傻站在这，快想办法！
You're the brilliant one.
你不是最聪明的么
I've got something, but it's mad!
我有个主意，但是很疯狂！
Reducto
粉身碎骨！
Well, come on, then!
快上来啊！
Relashio
力松劲泄！
Keep moving!
快跑！
Now what?
接下来呢？
Reducto
粉身碎骨！
Hold on.
抓紧！
That was brilliant! Absolutely brilliant!
太厉害了！有才！
We're dropping!
下降了！
- I say we jump! - When?
- 我们跳吧！ - 什么时候？
Now!
现在！
He knows.
他知道了
You-Know-Who.
“神秘人”
He knows we broke into Gringotts.
他知道我们闯进了古灵阁
He knows what we took, and he knows we're hunting Horcruxes.
他知道我们拿了什么，他也知道我们在找魂器
- How is it you know? - I saw him.
- 他怎么知道的？ - 我让他知道的
You let him in? Harry, you can't do that!
你让他进入了你的思想？ 哈利，你不能这么做！
Hermione, I can't always help it!
赫敏，我有时控制不住！
Well, maybe I can. I don't know!
也许能吧，我也不知道
Never mind! What happened?
别争这个了，你看到了什么？
Well, he's angry...
他很愤怒…
and scared too.
也很惊恐
He knows, if we find and destroy all the Horcruxes, we'll be able to kill him.
他明白，如果我们毁了所有的魂器，就能杀了他
I reckon he'll stop at nothing to make sure we don't find the rest.
他会不惜一切代价阻止我们找到其他魂器
And there's more.
还有一个魂器
One of them is at Hogwarts.
就在霍格沃茨
What?
什么？
You saw it?
你看见了？
I saw the castle.
我看到了霍格沃茨城堡
And Rowena Ravenclaw.
还有罗伊纳·拉文克劳
It must have something to do with her.
一定是跟她有关
We have to go there, now!
我们必须去学校，现在就去！
Well, we can't do that!
我们不能现在动身！
We've got to plan, we've got to figure it out!
我们得制定计划，得好好想清楚！
Hermione, when have any of our plans ever actually worked?
赫敏，我们哪次计划顺利进行过？
We plan, we get there, all hell breaks loose.
等我们计划好了再去，就太迟了！
He's right! One problem...
他说得对！但是…
Snape's Headmaster now, we can't just move from the front door!
斯内普现在是校长，我们不能走正门啊！
Well, we'll go to Hogsmeade,
那…我们去霍格莫德
to Honeydukes.
去蜂蜜公爵
Take the secret passage in the cellar.
走地窖里的密道
It's...
他…
There's something wrong with him.
他有些不对劲
It's like, you know, in the past...
就好像，以前…
I've always been able to follow his thoughts.
我总能看到他的思想
And now everything just feels disconnected.
但现在都是杂乱无章的片段
Maybe it's the Horcruxes. Maybe he's growing weaker.
也许是因为魂器被毁，也许他正渐渐虚弱
Maybe he's dying!
也许他快死了！
No!
不对
No, it's.. it's more like he's wounded.
更像是受了伤
If anything, he feels more dangerous.
可以肯定一点，他比以往更危险了
- Right here. Come on! - Search everywhere.
- 在这儿，快点！ - 仔细搜查
Go, move!
快去!
Faster!
快!
In here, Potter. Come on, move!
到这来，波特
Did you look at him?
你看见他了吗？
- For a second I thought that was... - I know. Dumbledore!
- 我差点以为是… - 我懂，像邓布利多
Harry?
哈利？
I can see you in this.
我能从这里看见你
Bloody fools, what were you thinking, coming here?
你们几个笨蛋，来这干什么？
Have you any idea how dangerous it is?
知道这有多危险吗？
You're Aberforth, Dumbledore's brother.
你是阿不福思，邓布利多的弟弟
It's you who I've been seeing in here.
我在镜子里看到的就是你
You're the one who sent Dobby.
是你派多比救我的
- Why've you left him? - He's dead.
- 他怎么没跟你们一起？ - 他死了
Sorry to hear it. I liked that elf.
真是可惜，我喜欢那只小精灵
Who gave that to you?
谁给你的？
The mirror?
那面镜子？
Mundungus Fletcher, 'bout a year ago.
蒙顿格斯·弗莱奇，约一年前
Dung had no right selling that to you. It belongs to...
蒙顿格斯没权给你，它属于…
Sirius...
小天狼星…
Albus told me.
阿不思告诉我了
He also told me you'd likely be hacked off,
他还说要是你发现了镜子在我这
...if you ever found that I had it. But, ask yourself;
肯定会生气的，不过你扪心自问
Where would you be if I didn't?
要是不在我这你会怎样？
Do you have any others much?From the Order?
有其他凤凰社成员的消息么？
The Order's finished.
凤凰社完了
You-Know-Who's won,
“神秘人”已经赢了
...anyone who says otherwise is killing themselves.
谁敢不这么说就是自寻死路
We need to get into Hogwarts, tonight.
我们要进入霍格沃茨，就今晚
Dumbledore gave us a job to do.
邓布利多给了我们一项任务
Did he now...
是吗…
Nice job? Easy?
轻松愉快的好任务么？
We've been hunting Horcruxes.
我们在找魂器
And we think the last one's inside the castle.
我们认为最后一件就在城堡里
But we'll need your help getting in.
但需要你的帮助才能进去
Which job my brother has given you no, it's a suicide mission.
我哥给的这哪是什么任务啊，简直是自杀行动
Do yourself a favor, boy. Go home!
拜托，孩子，回家去吧！
Live a little longer.
还能多活几天
Dumbledore trusted me to see this through.
邓布利多相信我能完成任务
What makes you think you can trust him?
你怎么知道你能相信他？
What makes you think you can believe anything my brother told you?
你怎么知道我哥跟你说的话都可信？
And in all the time you knew him...
你认识他这么久
Did he ever mention my name?
他可曾提起过我？
Did he ever mentioned hers?
可曾提起过她？
- Why should he... - Keep secrets.You tell me?
- 他干嘛要… - 要保密？你说呢？
- I trusted him. - That's a boy's answer.
- 我信任他 - 这答案太幼稚了
A boy goes chasing Horcruxes on the word of a man who wouldn't even tell him where to start.
邓布利多连从何找起都没告诉你 你就为他的片面之词搜集魂器？
You're lying!
你骗人！
Not just on me, that doesn't matter. To yourself as well.
你骗我不要紧，但你在骗你自己
That's what a fool does.
这是愚蠢之举
You don't strike me as a fool, Harry Potter!
我看你不像是蠢人啊，哈利·波特！
So, I'll ask you again, there must be a reason.
我再问一遍，是什么原因
I'm not interested in what happened between you and your brother.
我对你们兄弟间的恩怨不感兴趣
I don't care that you've given up.
我不在乎你已经放弃战斗
I trusted the man I knew.
我信任邓布利多
We need to get into the castle tonight.
我们今晚要进入霍格沃茨
You know what to do.
你知道该做什么
Where've you sent her?
你让她去哪儿了？
You'll see.
你会知道的
Soon enough.
很快
That's your sister, Ariana. Isn't it?
那是你妹妹，阿利安娜，是吧？
She died very young, didn't she?
她很年轻就过世了，是么？
My brother sacrificed many things, Mr. Potter.On his journey to find power.
我哥为了追求力量牺牲了许多东西，波特先生
Including Ariana.
包括阿利安娜
And she was devoted to him.
她很崇拜他
He gave her everything,
他给了她一切
...but time.
却没给她时间
Thank you, Mr. Dumbledore.
谢谢您，邓布利多先生
He did save our lives twice!
他救了我们两次
Kept an eye on us on that mirror.
还通过镜子关注我们
That doesn't seem like someone who's given up!
这不像是要放弃战斗的人
She's coming back.
她回来了
What's that with her?
她后边是谁？
Neville!
纳威！
- How you look... - Like hell, I reckon.
- 你怎么这么… - 狼狈，我知道
This is nothing.
这没什么
Seamus is worse.
西莫比我还惨
Hey, Ab!
嘿，阿不！
We've got a couple more coming through.
我们还有几个人要过来
Don't remember this on the Marauder's Map.
不记得地图上有这条道啊
That's because it never existed till now.
因为是新开通的
The seven secret passages were sealed off, before the start of the year.
原来7条密道开学前就被封了
This is the only way in or out, now.
现在只有这一条路可以进出
The grounds are crawled with Death Eaters and Dementors.
到处都是食死徒和摄魂怪
How about Mr.Snape as Headmaster?
斯内普校长当得怎么样啊？
Hardly ever seen.
我都没见过他
It's the Carrows who's watch out for.
一直是卡罗兄妹在监视学生
Carrows?
卡罗兄妹？
Yeah. Brother and sister. Incharge of discipline.
是啊，管纪律的
They like punishment, the Carrows.
他们喜欢体罚
They did that to you?
他们把你弄这样的？
Why?
为什么啊？
Today's Dark Arts lesson was practicing the Cruciatus curse.
今天黑魔法防御术课要练钻心咒
On first years.
对一年级新生用
I refused.
我不愿意
Hogwarts has changed.
霍格沃茨已经变了
Let's have a bit of fun, shall we?
来开心一下吧！
Hey, listen up you lot!
嘿，看我带什么来了
I've for you a surprise.
有惊喜喔
No more Aberforth's cook gonna help.
但愿不是阿不福思做的饭
We'll be surprised if we can digest that.
我还能消化它就已经是惊喜了
- Oh my! - Harry!
- 噢，天呐！ - 哈利！
Get the word out to Remus and the others, that Harry is back.
去告诉卢平他们，哈利回来了
Okay, okay!
好啦，好啦！
Let's not kill him before You-Know-Who does.
不用等“神秘人”，他就先被我们抱死了
...Do you read? We've a new weather report.Lightning has struck.
…收到了吗？最新天气预报，闪电已划破长空
I repeat: Lightning has struck.
重复，闪电已划破长空
What's the fun, Harry?
有什么计划，哈利？
Okay.
好吧…
There's something we need to find.
我们要找一样东西
Something hidden here, in the castle.
有一样东西就藏在城堡里
And it may help us to defeat You-Know-Who.
可能会有助于我们打败“神秘人”
- Alright, what is it? - We don't know.
- 好吧，什么东西？ - 不知道
- Where is it? - We don't know that either.
- 它在哪儿？ - 也不知道
I realize there's not much to go on.
我们知道的信息不多
That's nothing to go on.
根本就没有信息
I think it has something to do with Ravenclaw.
我觉得它跟拉文克劳有关
It'll be small, easily concealed.
应该很小巧，易于藏匿
Anyone, any ideas?
有人想到什么吗？
Well, there's Rowena Ravenclaw's lost diadem.
是罗伊纳·拉文克劳的丢失的冠冕
Oh, bloody hell! Here we go!
天啊，又开始了！
Lost diadem of Ravenclaw?
拉文克劳丢失的冠冕？
Hasn't anyone heard of this?
有人听说过吗？
It's quite famous.
很有名的
Yes. But, Luna, it's lost.
听说过，但是卢娜，冠冕已经丢了
For centuries. There's no person alive today who's seen it.
丢了几百年了，没有活人见过它
Excuse me, can someone tell me what bloody diadem is?
不好意思，谁能告诉我冠冕是什么鬼东西？
It's a sort of crown.
是一个皇冠
You know, like a tiara.
像头饰那样的
Harry!
哈利！
Hi, there.
嗨，你好
Six months she doesn't see me and it's like I'm a frankie first-year.
6个月没见她就像不认识我似的
I'm her brother!
我可是她哥啊！
- She's got lots of them, but she's got only one Harry. - Shut up, Seamus!
- 哥哥有很多，可哈利只有一个 - 闭嘴，西莫！
What is it, Ginny?
怎么了，金妮？
Snape knows... he knows that Harry was spotted in Hogsmeade.
斯内普发现了…他发现哈利去霍格莫德了
Many of you are surely wondering, why I have summoned you at this hour.
你们一定很纳闷，我为什么大半夜叫你们集合
It's come to my attention, that earlier this evening...
今晚早些时候，我发现…
Harry Potter was sighted in Hogsmeade.
哈利·波特出现在霍格莫德
Now...
现在…
should anyone...
要是有人…
student or staff attempt to aid Mr. Potter?
不论是学生还是教员，胆敢协助波特先生
They will be punished in a manner consistent with the severity of their transcription, further more...
都将受到与其行为同等严重的惩罚，不仅如此
Any person found to have knowledge of these events...
要是有人知道什么情况…
who fails to come forward...
却隐瞒不报…
...will be treated as equally guilty.
也将受到严惩
Another...
还有…
If anyone in here has any knowledge of Mr. Potter's movements this evening.
要是有人知道波特先生今晚的行动
I invite them to step forward.
我建议你最好站出来
Now!
就现在
It seems, despite your exhaustive defensive strategies,
看来您貌似滴水不漏的防御措施…
...you still have a bit of security problem, Headmaster.
还是有安全隐患啊，校长…
I'm afraid it's quite extensive.
隐患还不小呢
How dare you stand where he stood?
你怎么还有脸站在他的位置上？
Tell them how it happened that night?Tell them how you looked him in the eye...
告诉大家那晚发生了什么！告诉大家你是怎样看着他的眼睛…
A man who trusted you, and killed him.
他那么信任你，你却杀了他
Tell them!
说啊！
Harry.
哈利
Potter?
波特？
I know that many of you will want to fight.
我知道你们很多人都想反抗
Some of you may even think that to fight is wise.
甚至有人还以为反抗是明智的
But this is folly.
真是愚蠢
Give me Harry Potter.
交出哈利·波特
Do this and none shall be harmed.
交出他，大家就相安无事
Give me Harry Potter, and I shall leave Hogwarts untouched.
交出哈利·波特，我保证霍格沃茨不受损害
Give me Harry Potter, and you will be rewarded.
交出哈利·波特，我会给你们奖赏
You have one hour.
你们有1小时时间
What're you waiting for? Someone grab him!
还等什么？快抓住他！
Students out of bed!
学生下床了！
- Students in the corridor! - They're supposed to be out of bed,
- 学生都跑到走廊里了！ - 他们应该下床
you blithering idiot!
你这啰嗦的白痴！
Sorry ma'am.
抱歉，夫人
As it happens, Mr. Filch...
既然你来了，费尔奇先生…
Your arrival is most opportune.
来得正好
If you would, I would like you please, to lead Miss Parkinson
如果可以的话，我想请你把帕金森小姐
and the rest of Slytherin house, from the hall.
和斯莱特林学院的其他同学，都带走
Exactly where is it I'll be leading 'em to, ma'am?
带他们去哪儿啊，夫人？
The dungeons would do.
地牢
I presume you have a reason for returning, Potter.
你一定是有事才回来的，波特
What is it you need?
你需要什么？
Time, Professor. As much as you can get me.
时间，教授，越多越好
Do what you have to do.
做你应做的事去吧
I'll secure the castle.
我来守护城堡
Potter...
波特…
It's good to see you.
很高兴见到你
It's good to see you too, Professor.
很高兴见到你，教授
Hold the fort, Neville.
守住城堡
Harry!
哈利！
Hermione and I've been thinking, it doesn't matter if we find a Horcrux.
我跟赫敏刚才在想，就算我们找到了所有魂器也没用
What do you mean?
什么意思？
Unless we can destroy it.
除非你能毁了它
So, we were thinking...
所以我们就想到…
Well, Ron was thinking, it was Ron's idea.
是罗恩想到的，是罗恩的主意
It's completely brilliant.
他真是太聪明了
You destroyed Tom Riddle's diary with a Basilisk's fang, right?
你不是用蛇怪的牙毁了汤姆·里德尔的日记吗？
Well, me and Hermione did remind where we might find one.
我和赫敏可以去找毒牙
Okay.
好的
Okay, but take this.
去吧，带着这个
That way, you can find me when you get back.
这样你们回来时就能找到我了
Where're you going?
你要去哪儿？
Ravenclaw common room, Gotta start somewhere.
拉文克劳的公共休息室，先找找看吧
Harry! Harry!
哈利！哈利！
Let me get this straight, Professor...
我得问清楚了，教授
You're actually giving us permission to do this?
您真允许我们这么做？
That is correct, Longbottom.
没错，隆巴顿
To blow it up! Boom!
那可是爆炸啊！爆炸！
Boom!
快去！
Wicked!
那好吧
But how on earth are we gonna do that?
我们要怎么炸啊？
Why don't you confer with Mr. Finnigan?
你可以去请教斐尼甘先生啊
As I recall, he has a particular proclivity for pyro-technics.
我记得他对引爆可是相当有天赋
I can bring it down.
我能炸了它
That's the spirit! Away, you go.
这才像话，快去吧
You do realize, of course, we can't keep out You-Know-Who indefinitely.
你知道的，我们阻挡不了“神秘人”太长时间的
That doesn't mean we can't delay him.
我们可以拖住他
And his name is Voldemort. Filius, you might as well use it.
还有，他的名字是伏地魔 菲利乌斯，你也应该这样叫他
He's come to try to kill you, either way!
反正他都要来杀你
Piertotum Locomotor.
石墩出动！
Hogwarts is threatened.
霍格沃茨危在旦夕
Man the boundaries! Protect us. Do your duty...to our school.
守卫边界，保护师生，为我学校，尽职尽责！
I've always wanted to use that spell!
我想用这个咒语很久了
Protego MaximaFianto Duri
超强盔甲护身，统统护卫
Repello InimigotumProtego Maxima
Repello....Fianto DuriRepello Inimigotum
超强盔甲护身，统统护卫
Harry, wait!
哈利，等等！
I need to talk to you!
我有话要说！
- I'm a bit pre-occupied at the moment, Luna. - You don't know anything where you're going.
- 我有点忙，卢娜 - 你不知道要去哪儿找
You're wasting your time!
你在浪费时间！
Look, we'll talk later, okay, Luna?
一会儿再说吧…
- Harry? - Later.
- 哈利？ - 再说吧
Harry Potter, you listen to me right now!
哈利·波特，你现在就给我听着！
Do you remember what Cho said about Rowena Ravenclaw's diadem?
你还记得秋是怎么说拉文克劳冠冕的吗？
There is not a person alive who's seen it.
没有活人见过它
It's obvious, isn't it?
显然
We have to talk to someone who's dead.
我们得去问死人
It's very impressive, isn't it?
好壮观啊
If you've to find her, you'll find her down there.
要找她的话，她就在那里面
- Aren't you coming? - No.
- 你不一跟我去？ - 不了
I think it's best if you two talk alone.
我觉得最好让你俩单独谈
She's very shy.
她很害羞的
You're the Grey Lady.
你是格雷女士
The ghost of Ravenclaw tower.
拉文克劳塔楼的幽灵
I do not answer to that name!
我不叫那个名字！
No, I'm sorry, I'm sorry!
对不起，对不起！
It's Helena, isn't it?
是海莲娜
Helena Ravenclaw, Rowena's daughter.
海莲娜·拉文克劳，罗伊纳的女儿
Are you a friend of Luna's?
你是卢娜的朋友？
Yes.
是
And she thought you might be able to help me.
她说你能帮我
You seek my mother's diadem?
你要找我母亲的冠冕？
Yes.
是
That's right.
没错
Luna is kind.
卢娜很善良
Unlike so many of the others.
不像大多数人
But she was wrong, I cannot help you!
但她错了，我不能帮你！
Wait, please!
求你，别走！
I want to destroy it!
我要销毁它！
They never learn.
还是没有长进
Such a pity.
真遗憾
But, my Lord...
主人…
Shouldn't we wait?
我们不再等等吗？
Begin!
进攻！
I thought you want to do it. Isn't it, Helena?
你也想这样不是吗，海莲娜？
You want to destroy it?
你也想毁了它
Another swore to destroy it, many years ago.
许多年前有一个人也承诺会毁了它
A strange boy with a strange name.
一个奇怪的男孩，名字也很怪
Tom Riddle.
汤姆·里德尔
But he lied.
但他骗了我
He's lied to many people.
他骗过许多人
I know what he's done! I know who he is!
我知道他干了什么！我知道他是谁！
He defiled it, with dark magic!
他用黑魔法玷污了冠冕！
I can destroy it.
我能毁了它
Once and for all.
彻底销毁
But only if you tell me where he hid it?
但你得先告诉我他把冠冕藏哪儿了
You do know, where he hid it?
你肯定知道他藏哪儿了
Don't you, Helena?
不是吗，海莲娜？
You just have to tell me.
告诉我吧
Please!
求你了！
Strange!
奇怪
You remind me of him a bit.
我觉得你有点像他
It's here, in the castle.
冠冕就在城堡里
In the place where everything is hidden.
在一个能藏下所有东西的地方
If you have to ask...
如果你还要问…
....you will never know.
你永远也不会知道
If you know...
如果你知道…
...you need only ask.
你只需开口问
Thank you!
谢谢你！
Tell Professor McGonagall. Remus and I will handle this side of the castle.
告诉麦格教授，我和莱姆斯负责城堡这边
Yes, sir!
是，先生！
Hey Dean, on second thoughts, tell Professor McGonagall
埃迪，还是告诉麦格教授
we might need one or two more wands this side.
这边再需要几个帮手吧
It is the quality of one's convictions that determine his success..
决定成败的是人信念的强弱
...not the number of followers.
而不是帮手的多少
Who said that?
谁说的？
Me.
我
You okay, Freddie?
你还好吗，弗雷德？
Yeah.
很好
Me too.
我也是
Harry talks in his sleep.
哈利做梦时说的
Do you know this?
你不知道？
No, of course, not!
我怎么会知道
Yeah? You and whose army?
来呀！就凭你们？
You do it.
你来
- I can't. - Yes, you can!
- 我不行 - 你行！
Neville!
纳威！
That went well.
一切顺利
Get inside! This way! Take cover! Take cover
快进去！
Ginny, Neville! You alright?
金妮！纳威！你们还好吧？
Never better!
再好不过了！
I feel like I can spit fire!
我觉得自己战火熊熊！
Have you seen Luna up here?
卢娜在上边吗？
Luna?
卢娜？
I'm mad for her. I think it about time I told her
我喜欢她！我现在就得告诉她
since wel probably both be dead by dawn.
不然天亮前我们可能都没命了！
I know.
我懂的
Bloody hell! We'll never find him on this.
该死！这可怎么找他啊
Here he is!
他在这儿！
- Just now... - Brilliant!
- 他刚刚… - 厉害
He just vanished.
他刚刚消失了
I just now I saw it.
我敢肯定我看见了
Maybe he's gone to the Room of Requirement.
他可能去了有求必应屋
It doesn't show up on the map, does it?
地图上无法显示有求必应屋
You said that last year.
你去年说的
That's right, I....I did.
没错，是我说的
Let's go.
走吧
Brilliant!
有才
Come on!
走！
Well, well...
很好…
What brings you here, Potter?
你来这儿干什么，波特？
I could ask you the same
我正想问你
You have something of mine.
你拿了我的魔杖
I'd like it back.
我要夺回来
What's wrong with the one you have?
现在这根怎么了？
It's my mother's.
我母亲的
It's powerful, but it's...
很强，但是…
..not the same.
这不一样
Doesn't quite understand me.
用着不顺手
You know what I mean?
明白我意思？
Why didn't you tell her?
你为什么没告诉她？
Bellatrix?
告诉贝拉特里克斯
You knew it was me.
你明知那就是我
You didn't say anything.
却什么都没说
Come on, Draco!
动手吧，德拉科！
Don't be a prat.
别傻站着了
Do it!
动手！
Easy!
别动！
Expelliarmus
除你武器！
Avada Kedavra
阿瓦达索命！
Stupefy
昏昏倒地！
This is my girlfriend, you bloody gits!
敢动我女朋友，你们死定了！
Got it!
找到了！
They've set the bloody place on fire!
快跑！他们把这鬼地方给点了！
Come on! This way!
快！这边！
We can't leave them!
不能丢下他们！
He's joking, right?
他开玩笑呢吧？！
If we die for them, Harry, I'm gonna kill you!
要是我们被他们拖死了我就杀了你！
Harry!
哈利！
My Lord?
主人？
Avada Kedavra!
阿瓦达索命！
Come Nagini, I need to keep you safe.
过来，纳吉尼，我得保证你的安全
It's the snake....
是那条蛇
....and she's the last one.
最后一件
It's the last Horcrux.
它是最后一件魂器
Look inside him, Harry.
进入他的思想，哈利
Find out where he is, if you find him, we can find the snake.
看看他在哪儿，找到他就能找到蛇
And we can end this!
我们就毁掉所有魂器了！
My Lord...
主人…
Might it be less...
也许…呃…
I should not be more prudent to call off this attack.
我还是建议停止大范围进攻
Simply seek the boy. Yourself.
您亲自去找那个男孩儿
I do not need to seek the boy...
我不需要找他
....before the night is out, he will come to me! Do you understand?
不出今晚，他自会找上门！ 听懂了吗？
Look at me!
看着我！
How can you live with yourself, Lucius?
你怎么还有脸说？卢修斯！
I don't know.
我不知道
Go and find Severus.
去找西弗勒斯
Bring him to me.
带他来见我
I know where he is.
我知道他在哪儿了
Come on!
快上！
No!
不要！
You have performed extra-ordinary magic with this wand, My Lord,
仅这几个小时，您就用这根魔杖施展了
...in the last few hours alone.
高超的魔法，主人
No!
不！
No! I am extra-ordinary. But the wand resists me.
不对！高超的是我，而魔杖一直在反抗
There is no wand more powerful. Ollivander himself has said it.
没有魔杖比这根更强 奥利凡德也是这么说的
Tonight, when the boy comes. It will not fail you, I am sure of it...
今晚，等找到了那个男孩儿 魔杖不会让您失望的，我敢保证…
It answers to you, and you only.
魔杖听从您，只听从您一人
Does it?
是吗？
My Lord?
主人
The wand, does it truly answer to me?
魔杖真的听从于我吗？
You're a clever man, Severus.
你是个聪明人，西弗勒斯
Surely you must know...
你肯定知道…
- Where does its true loyalty lie? - With you...
- 魔杖到底效忠于谁？ - 效忠您…
Of course, My Lord.
当然是您，主人
The Elder Wand cannot serve me properly, because I am not its true master.
老魔杖没有好好为我效力 因为我不是它真正的主人
The Elder Wand belongs to the wizard who killed its last owner.
老魔杖属于杀死它前任主人的巫师
You killed Dumbledore, Severus.
是你杀了邓布利多，西弗勒斯
While you live, the Elder Wand cannot truly be mine.
只要你活着，老魔杖就不可能真正属于我
You've been a good and faithful servant, Severus.
你一直是个忠心耿耿的好仆人，西弗勒斯
But only I can live forever.
但只有我…才能永生
My Lord...
主人…
Nagini, kill!
纳吉尼，杀！
Take it... Take it up, please!
把这…拿去…求你…
Give me something! Quickly, a flask. Anything!
给我个容器！快点，瓶子之类的！
Take them to the Pensieve.
放到冥想盆里
Look at me...
看着我…
You really have your mother's eyes.
眼睛跟你妈妈一样…
You've fought valiantly, but in vain...
你们的抵抗很英勇，但都是徒劳的…
I do not wish this. Every drop of magical blood spilled is a terrible waste.
我不希望发生这样的事 每一滴巫师的血都是严重的损失
I, therefore command my forces to retreat...
因此，我会下令撤军…
In their absence, dispose your dead with dignity,
之后，你们可以体面地安置死者
Harry Potter, I now speak directly to you.
哈利·波特，现在我直接对你说
On this night, you have allowed your friends to die for you, rather than face me yourself.
今晚，你居然听任朋友为你而死 而不愿亲自来面对我
There is no greater dishonor. Join me in the Forbidden Forrest...
真是太可耻了 来禁林找我…
...and confront your fate.
面对自己的命运
If you do not do this, I shall kill every last man,
如果你不来，我会杀光所有试图窝藏你的人.
woman and child who tries to conceal you from me.
不论男女老幼
Where's everybody?
大家都哪儿去了？
Harry?
哈利？
Oh, come on! Don't be sad on it,
拜托，别这样
she's passed.
她去了
There, she's gone.
是的，她走了…
Freak! Come here! I'm gonna tell mommy! You're freak!
怪胎！别跑！我要告诉妈妈！你是怪胎！
You're freak, Lily!
你是怪胎，莉莉！
Come here!
过来！
She's jealous. She's ordinary and you're special.
她嫉妒你，她只是凡人 而你却与众不同
That's not true, Severus.
别这么说，西弗勒斯
Gryffindor!
格兰芬多！
- Hi, I'm James. - Hi, I'm Lily.
- 你好，我是詹姆 - 你好，我是莉莉
Just like your father.
跟你爹一样，懒惰、傲慢
Don't say a word against my father!
不许说我父亲坏话！
Masters shall be reunited once more!
无辜者的鲜血将流淌，主仆将再度联手！
Severus.
西弗勒斯
No, don't kill me!
别杀我！
The prophecy did not refer to a woman.
预言没说是女人
It spoke about a boy born at the end of the July.
说的是一个七月底出生的男孩儿
Yes, but he thinks it's her son!
是，他认为是莉莉的儿子！
He intends to hunt them down and to kill them.
他要找到他们一家，然后杀光
Hide him... hide them all. I beg you!
把他们藏起来，都藏起来，我求你了！
What would you give me in exchange, Severus?
你拿什么跟我交换，西弗勒斯？
- Anything. - Harry...
- 什么都行 - 哈利…
Harry, you were so loved.
哈利，我们好爱你
So loved! Harry, mama loves you.
非常爱！哈利，妈妈爱你
Dadda loves you.
爸爸也爱你
Harry, be safe.
哈利要活下去
- Be strong. - Avada Kedavra!
- 要坚强！ - 阿瓦达索命！
You said you would keep her safe.
你说过…你说过的…你会保证她的安全！
Lily and James...
莉莉和詹姆…
..put their faith in the wrong person, Severus.
他们信错了人，西弗勒斯
Rather like you.
你不也是么
The boy survives.
她儿子还活着
He doesn't need protection, the Dark Lord has gone.
他不需要保护，黑魔王已经死了！
The Dark Lord will return.
黑魔王还会回来的！
And when he does, the boy will be in terrible danger!
到时那孩子就会有危险！
He has her eyes.
他眼睛和他妈妈一样
If you truly loved her...
如果你真的爱她…
No one, can know.
不许告诉任何人
I shall never reveal the best of you, Severus.
你是要我永不透露你善良的一面？
Your word?
你保证？
Can you risk your life every day to protect the boy?
你能每天都冒生命危险保护这孩子吗？
He possesses no measurable talent, his arrogance rivals even that of his father
他天资平庸，跟他爹一样傲慢无礼
and he seems to relish in his fame
有点名气就沾沾自喜
Don't say a word against my father!
不许说我父亲坏话！
James Potter, lazy, arrogant.
詹姆·波特，懒惰、傲慢
- My father was a great man! - Your father was a swine!
- 我父亲是个伟大的人！ - 你父亲是个卑鄙小人！
Drink it, it will contain the curse to your hand, for the time being.
喝了，它能把魔咒封在手部，但只是暂时的
- It will spread, Albus. - How a long?
- 迟早会扩散 - 我还有多少时间？
Maybe a year.
大概一年
Don't ignore me, Severus.
别走，西弗勒斯
We both know Lord Voldemort has ordered the Malfoy boy to murder me.
你我都知道伏地魔王已经派马尔福来杀我
But should he fail, I should presume the Dark Lord will turn to you.
如果他失败了，我想伏地魔定会让你动手
You must be the one to kill me, Severus.
必须由你杀死我，西弗勒斯
It is the only way.
只有这一个办法
Only then, will the Dark Lord trust you completely.
只有这样，伏地魔才会完全信任你
It will come a time, when Harry Potter,must be told something.
等时机成熟，你一定要告诉哈利·波特一件事
But you must wait, until Voldemort is at his most vulnerable.
但一定要等到伏地魔最虚弱的时刻
Must be told what?
告诉他什么？
On the night, Lord Voldemort went to Godric's Hollow to kill Harry...
伏地魔去戈德里克山谷要杀哈利的那个晚上…
And Lily Potter cast herself between them...
莉莉·波特用自己的身体挡在他们之间时…
...the curse rebounded.
魔咒反弹了
When that happens, a part of Voldemort's soul...
那时，伏地魔灵魂的一个碎片…
...latched itself onto the only living thing it could find...
附着在了屋里唯一的活物身上…
...Harry himself.
在哈利体内
There's a reason Harry can speak with snakes...
哈利会蛇佬腔…
There's a reason he can look into Lord Voldemort's mind...
能连接伏地魔的思想，都是有原因的
A part of Voldemort lives inside him.
伏地魔的一部分就活在他体内
So, when the time comes...
就是说，到时候…
...the boy must die?
那男孩儿就必须死？
Yes... yes. He must die.
是的…他必须死
You've kept him alive, so he can die at the proper moment?
你让他活着，就为了让他在适当的时候再死？
You've been raising him like a pig for slaughter.
你养着他就像养一头待宰的猪
Don't tell me now, that you've grown to care for the boy.
可别跟我说，你对他产生感情了
Expecto Patronum
呼神护卫！
Lily!
莉莉！
After all this time?
这么久了你还是…
Always.
一直都是
So, when the time comes...
那么，到时候…
...the boy must die?
那男孩儿就必须死？
Yes.
是
He must die. And Voldemort himself must do it.
他必须死，而且必须由伏地魔动手
That is essential.
这才是关键
- Where've you been? - I thought you went to the forest.
- 你去哪儿了？ - 我还以为你去了禁林
I'm going there now.
我这就去
Are you mad? No...
你疯了吗？别去
You can't give yourself up to him.
你不能向他投降
What is it, Harry?
怎么了，哈利？
What is it you know?
你知道什么了？
There's a reason I can hear them.
我能听见是有原因的
The Horcruxes.
听见魂器
I think I've known for a while.
我应该早就想到了
And I think you have, too.
我觉得你们应该也想到了
- I'll go with you. - No, kill the snake.
- 我要跟你一起去 - 不行，你们得杀了那条蛇
Kill the snake, and then it's just him!
杀了蛇，就只剩他了！
(我在结束时打开)
I'm ready to die.
我就要死了
Resurrection Stone.
复活石
You've been so brave, sweetheart.
你一直很勇敢，宝贝
Why are you here? All of you.
你们怎么都在这儿？
We never left.
我们从未离开
Does...
那…
Does it hurt?
疼吗？
Dying?
死？
Quicker than falling asleep.
比睡着还快
You're nearly there, son.
只差一步了，儿子
I'm sorry.
对不起
I never wanted any of you to die for me.
我从来没想过要你们为我而死
And, Remus, your son?
莱姆斯，你刚有儿子…
Others will tell him what his mother and father died for.
他会知道父母是为何牺牲的
One day, he'll understand.
总有一天，他会明白
You'll stay with me?
你们会陪着我么？
Until the end.
直到最后
And he won't be able to see you?
别人看不见你们么？
No.
看不见
We're here, you see.
我们在你心里
Stay close to me.
陪在我身边
Always.
一直都是
No sign of him, My Lord.
他还是没出现，主人
I thought he would come.
我以为他会来
Harry, no!
哈利，不要！
- What're yeh doin' here? - Quiet!
- 为什么要来？ - 安静！
Harry Potter...
哈利·波特…
...The Boy Who Lived...
大难不死的男孩儿…
...come to die.
前来受死吧
Avada Kedavra
阿瓦达索命！
You can't help...
你帮不了…
Harry, you wonderful boy...
哈利，你真是好孩子
You brave, brave man!
最最勇敢的男子汉！
Let us walk.
我们走吧
Professor, what is that?
教授，那是什么？
Something beyond either of our help.
是我们无能为力的东西
A part of Voldemort sent here to die.
伏地魔的一部分在这里等待死亡
And exactly where are we?
那这里到底是哪儿？
I was going to ask you that.
我正想问你
Where would you say that we are?
你说我们是在哪儿？
Well, it looks like King's Cross station.
看样子像国王十字车站
Only cleaner...
但是更干净…
....and without all the trains.
没有火车
King's Cross, is that right?
国王十字车站，真的吗？
This is, as they say, "your" party.
这就是人们说的:“你的地盘”
I expect you now realize that you and Voldemort...
你现在应该知道你和伏地魔…
...have been connected by something other than fate.
你们的命运紧紧缠绕在一起
Since that night in Godric's Hollow, all those years ago.
从多年前戈德里克山谷那一晚开始
So it's true then, sir.
这么说是真的了，教授
A part of him lives within me, doesn't it?
他的一部分活在我的体内，是吗？
Did.
曾经在
It's been just destroyed many moments ago by none other than Voldemort himself.
那一部分刚刚被伏地魔亲自摧毁了
You, were the Horcrux he never meant to make, Harry.
你是他无意间造就的魂器，哈利
- I have to go back, haven't I? - Oh, that's up to you.
- 我必须回去，是吗？ - 这由你做主
- I've a choice? - Oh, yes!
- 我可以选择？ - 是的！
We're in King's Cross, you say.
你说我们在国王十字车站
I think if you so decide, you'll be able to board a train.
我想如果你迫切要回去的话 应该会出现一列火车
And where would it take me?
它会把我带到哪儿呢？
On.
前方
Voldemort has the Elder Wand.
伏地魔拥有老魔杖？
True.
不错
- And the snake's still alive? - Yes.
- 那条蛇还活着？ - 是的
And I've nothing to kill it with?
可我没有武器可以杀它
Help will always be given at Hogwarts, Harry.To those who ask for it.
在霍格沃茨，那些需要帮助的人总能得到帮助，哈利
I've always pride of myself on my ability to turn a phrase.
我一直自诩很善于措辞
Words are, in my not so humble opinion...
以我的愚见，语言…
..are most inexhaustible source of magic.
就像用之不竭的魔法
Capable of inflicting injury and remedies.
可以中伤他人，亦可抚慰忧伤
But I would in this case...
不过我现在想…
...amend my original statement to this:
把我的原话稍作改动，变成
Help, will always be given at Hogwarts,To those who deserve it.
在霍格沃茨，那些值得帮助的人总能得到帮助
Do not pity the dead, Harry...
不要怜悯死者，哈利…
Pity the living.
怜悯活着的人
And above all...
尤其是那些…
....all those who live without love.
生命中没有爱的人
Professor, my mother's Patronus...
教授，我母亲的守护神…
...was a doe, wasn't it?
是只母鹿，对吧？
As the same as Professor Snape's.
跟斯内普教授的一样
It's curious, don't you think?
你不觉得很奇怪么？
Actually, if I think about it...
其实要我说…
...it doesn't seem curious at all!
这一点也不奇怪
I'll be going now, Harry.
我要走了，哈利
Professor?
教授？
Is this all real?
这是真实的吗？
Or is it just happening inside my head?
还是只是我脑海里的臆想？
Of course it's happening inside your head, Harry.
当然是你脑海里的臆想，哈利
Why should that mean, that it's not real?
但为什么那就不能是真实的呢？
Professor?
教授？
What should I do?
我该怎么做？
Professor!
教授？
My Lord, My Lord... Are you hurt?
主人，我的主人，你受伤了？
I don't need your help.
我用不着你帮忙！
The boy... Is he dead?
那男孩儿…死了没？
Is he alive?
他还活着么？
Draco, is he alive?
德拉科还活着么？
Dead.
死了
Who is that? Hagrid's carrying?
那是谁？海格抱着的是谁？
Neville, who is it?
纳威，那是谁？
Harry Potter...
哈利·波特…
- ...is dead! - No!No!
- 死了！ - 不！不会的！
Silence!
安静！
Stupid girl!
愚蠢！
Harry Potter...is dead!
哈利·波特死了！
From this day forth...
从今天起…
...you'll put your faith in me.
你们都得追随我
Harry Potter is dead!
哈利波特死了！
And now it's the time to declare yourself.
现在表明立场吧！
Come forward and join us...or die!
要加入我的走上前…否则就死！
Draco!
德拉科！
Draco.
德拉科
Come.
过来
Well done, Draco.
很好，德拉科
Well done!
非常好！
Well, I must say I'd hoped for better.
哈，比我期望的要糟糕啊
And who might you be, young man?
你是哪位，年轻人？
Neville Longbottom.
纳威·隆巴顿
Well, Neville, I'm sure we can find a place for you in our rank.
好吧纳威，我保证你会有用武之地的
I'd like to say something.
我有话要说
Well, Neville, I'm sure we'd all be fascinated to hear what you have to say.
好吧纳威，我倒要听听你想说什么
- Doesn't matter that Harry is gone. - Stand down, Neville!
- 哈利死了也没关系 - 别说了，纳威！
People die everyday!
每天都有人死！
Friends, family.
朋友，家人…
Yeah...
是…
We lost Harry tonight.
今晚我们失去了哈利
He's still with us.
但他还在
In here.
在我们心里
So as Fred, Remus...
弗雷德、莱姆斯…
Tonks...
唐克斯…
All of them.
他们都在
They didn't die in vain.
他们没有白白牺牲！
But you will.
但是你会！
Because you're wrong!
因为你错了！
Harry's heart did beat for us.
哈利是为我们而战
For all of us!
为我们所有人！
It's not over!
还没结束！
Confringo
霹雳爆炸！
Come on!
回来战斗！回来！
All remain into the castle.
大家都进城堡！
We have to kill the snake.
我们得杀了那只蛇
Use this!
拿着毒牙！
Neville!
纳威！
Not my daughter, you bitch!
不许碰我女儿，贱人！
Hey, you were right...
其实你说对了…
...when you told Professor Snape that wand was failing you.
你跟斯内普教授说那根魔杖不听你的
It will always fail...
它本来…
I killed Snape!
我杀了斯内普！
But what if the wand never belonged to Snape?
可如果魔杖根本不属于斯内普呢？
What if its allegiance is always to someone else?
如果魔杖效忠的一直另有其人呢？
Oh, come on, Tom...
来吧，汤姆…
Let's finish this the way we started.
我们开始的由我们来结束
Together! Die!
做个了断吧！
Harry!
哈利！
Why didn't it work for him? The Elder Wand?
老魔杖为什么不听他的呢？
It answered to somebody else.
老魔杖效忠的另有其人
When he killed Snape, he thought the wand would become his.
他以为杀了斯内普，魔杖就会属于他
But the thing is...
但实际上…
The wand never belonged to Snape.
魔杖从来都不属于斯内普
It was Draco, who disarmed Dumbledore that night in the Astronomy tower.
天文塔那晚，邓布利多是被德拉科解除武器的
From that moment on and the wand answered him,
从那时起，魔杖就效忠于他
Until, the other night when I disarmed Draco.
直到那晚他被我解除武器
At Malfoy Manor.
在马尔福庄园
So, that means...
那就是说…
It's mine!
魔杖属于我！
- What should we do with it? - We?
- 我们该怎么处理？ - 我们？
Just saying, that's the Elder Wand.
我是说，那可是老魔杖啊
The most powerful wand in the world.
世界上最厉害的魔杖
With that, he'd be invincible.
有了它，就能战无不胜
(19年后)
Together.
一起走
- Bag? - Yeah.
- 书包？ - 拿了
Jumper?
毛衣？
I'm gonna miss you.
我会想你的
Here they come.
他们来了
Dad?
爸爸
What if I am put in Slytherin?
要是我被分到斯莱特林怎么办？
Albus Severus Potter. You were named after two Headmasters of Hogwarts.
阿不思·西弗勒斯·波特 你是以霍格沃茨两位校长的名字命名的
One of them was a Slytherin. And he was the bravest man I've ever known.
其中之一就毕业于斯莱特林学院 他也是我见过的最勇敢的人
- But just say if I am... - Then Slytherin house...
- 可是如果我… - 那么斯莱特林学院
...will have gained a wonderful young wizard.
就会拥有一名优秀的小巫师
But listen...
但是…
If it really means that much to you, you can choose Gryffindor.
如果你真的很在意，你可以选择格兰芬多
The Sorting Hat takes your choice into account.
分院帽会考虑你的选择
- Really? - Really.
- 真的吗？ - 真的
- Ready? - Ready.
- 准备好了？ - 好了